www.HDcmct.com
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==-- 影片压制: 如烟 招募Q号:76846146
Are you here to kill me?
你前来杀我?
I know what this is.
我深知眼前何物
I've seen one before. Many, many years ago.
多年前曾见过
It belonged to a man I met in a half-remembered dream.
隐约记得该物主
A man possessed of some radical notions.
一个激进的男人
What is the most resilient parasite?
世上适应力最强的附寄物是什么
A bacteria? A virus?
细菌?病毒?
An intestinal worm?
蛔虫
What Mr. Cobb is trying to say...
高比先生所指是…
An idea.
意识
Resilient. Highly contagious.
生生不息 极易感染
Once an idea has taken hold of the brain, it's almost impossible to eradicate.
其据脑海 安能根绝
An idea that is fully formed, fully understood, that sticks.
一旦扎根 根深蒂固
Right in there somewhere.
盘亘脑海
For someone like you to steal?
便于你们偷取
Yes. In the dream state, your conscious defenses are lowered...
对 睡梦状态意识防卫会减弱
...and that makes your thoughts vulnerable to theft.
便于我们从中盗取信息
It's called extraction.
我们就是盗梦者
Mr. Saito, we can train your subconscious to defend itself...
齐藤先生 我们训练你潜意识防卫
...from even the most skilled extractor.
去抵抗技艺超凡的盗梦者
How can you do that?
何以保证?
Because I am the most skilled extractor.
因为鄙人是最技艺超凡的盗梦者
I know how to search your mind and find your secrets. I know the tricks.
我知晓读心探密 洞悉其术
And I can teach them to you, so that even when you're asleep...
能授与你 虽处睡梦状态
...your defense is never down.
意识防卫亦不减弱
Look, if you want my help, you're gonna have to be completely open with me.
若要我援手 要对我敞开心胸
I need to know my way around your thoughts better than your wife...
令我更甚你的亲眷
...better than your therapist, better than anyone.
了解你为人
If this is a dream, and you have a safe full of secrets...
假设这是场梦 你会有个装满秘密的保险箱
...I need to know what's in that safe.
然而我需要知道箱中何物
In order for this all to work, you need to completely let me in.
若要达成目的 必须对我敞开心胸
Enjoy your evening, gentlemen, as I consider your proposal.
晚上愉快 我会考虑你提议
He knows.
被他识穿
What's going on up there?
这里怎么了
Saito knows. He's playing with us.
齐藤洞悉此局 他在耍我们
Doesn't matter. I can get it here. Trust me.
没关系 会没问题 相信我
The information is in the safe.
资料在那保险箱里
He looked right at it when I mentioned secrets.
当我提及秘密时 他看了它一眼
What's she doing here?
她来干什么
Just head back to the room. All right? I'll take care of this.
你回房间 我会处理
Okay, make sure you do. We're here to work.
务必解决 我们是来工作
If I jumped, would I survive?
若跳下去 还能保命吗
With a clean dive, perhaps.
技术高的话 或许能保命
Mal, what are you doing here?
美颖 你在这干嘛
I thought you might be missing me.
我以为你很想见我
You know that I am.
确实如此
But I can't trust you anymore.
但我不再相信你
So what?
那又何如
Looks like Arthur's taste.
真像雅迪的品味
Actually, the subject is partial to postwar British painters.
目标特别偏爱战后大不列颠的画家作品
Please, have a seat.
请坐
Tell me...
告诉我
...do the children miss me?
孩子们想念我吗?
You can't imagine.
对你日思夜想
What are you doing?
你干嘛
Just getting some fresh air.
出外呼吸新鲜空气
Stay where you are, Mal.
留在这里
Goddamn it.
激死
Turn around.
转身
The gun, Dom.
杜文 放下枪
Please.
有劳
Now the envelope, Mr. Cobb.
高比先生 交出信封
Did she tell you? Or have you known all along?
她告诉你 抑或你早就知道
That you're here to steal from me, or that we are actually asleep?
知道你是来偷东西 抑或知道我们现处于梦空间?
I want to know the name of your employer.
谁指使你们前来
Ah, there's no use threatening him in a dream, right, Mal?
美颖 梦中要挟他人毫无作用
That depends on what you're threatening.
取决于你是怎么要挟
Killing him would just wake him up.
杀死他 只是唤醒他
But pain...
但痛击他…
Pain is in the mind.
他会感受到
And judging by the decor, we're in your mind, aren't we, Arthur?
依据室内摆设 我们处于你梦中?
- What are you doing? It's too soon. - But the dream's collapsing.
- 你干嘛 时候过早 - 但梦空间已在崩毁
I'm gonna try to keep Saito under a little bit longer. We're almost there.
拖延齐藤觉醒时间 我们快到手
He was close. Very close.
梦空间要崩毁
Stop him!
阻止他
This isn't gonna work. Wake him up.
估计成功 叫醒他
He won't wake.
他还在梦空间
- Give him the kick.  What?
- 堕醒他 - 什么
Dunk him.
推进浴缸
He's out.
他醒了
You came prepared, hmm?
你有备而来?
Not even my head of security knows this apartment. How did you find it?
连我的保安主管都不知道该地 你如何得知
It's difficult for a man of your position to keep a love nest like this secret...
位高权重者私筑爱巢 难以不走漏风声
...particularly where there's a married woman involved.
何况涉及已婚之妇
- She would never... - Yet here we are.
- 她不会… - 事已至此
- With a dilemma. - They're getting closer.
- 进退两难 - 他们逼近
- You got what you came for.  Well, that's not true.
- 你已拿到想要 - 不
You left out a key piece of information, didn't you?
你故意漏掉一条关键信息
You held something back because you knew what we were up to.
你知道我们的目的 所以有所保留
- Question is, why'd you let us in at all? - An audition.
- 问题是为何你让我们入你梦中 - 试探
- An audition for what? - Doesn't matter. You failed.
- 试探什么 - 不要紧 你已失败
We extracted every bit of information you had in there.
我们已拿到你藏捏的秘密
But your deception was obvious.
但你的骗局漏洞百出
- So leave me and go. - You don't seem to understand, Mr. Saito.
- 让我走吧 - 你似乎仍不明白 齐藤先生
That corporation that hired us, they won't accept failure.
幕后指使者只许行动成功
We won't last two days.
否则我们亦命不久矣
Cobb?
杜文?
Looks like I'm gonna have to do this a little more simply.
别不识抬举
Tell us what you know! Tell us what you know, now!
马上讲出你所知道
I've always hated this carpet.
最讨厌这地毯
It's stained and frayed in such distinctive ways.
特别易脏和磨损
But very definitely made of wool.
明显是羊毛毯
Right now...
但现在
...I'm lying on polyester.
明显是聚脂纤维地毯
Which means I'm not lying on my carpet, in my apartment.
换言之这里不是我的私巢
You have lived up to your reputation, Mr. Cobb.
杜文 你果然名下无虚
I'm still dreaming.
我仍在你设计的梦中
- How'd it go? - Not good.
- 情况如何 - 不如意
Dream within a dream, huh? I'm impressed.
梦中梦 令我大开眼界
But in my dream, you play by my rules.
不过在我梦中 必须按我规矩
Ah, yes, but you see, Mr. Saito...
没错 不过 齐藤先生
We're not in your dream.
我们并非在你梦中
We're in mine.
而是在我梦中
Asshole. How do you mess up the carpet?
蠢材 你搞错了地毯
- It wasn't my fault. - You're the architect.
- 不关我事 - 你是造梦师
I didn't know he was gonna rub his cheek on it!
我哪料到他能认出地毯材质
That's enough.
够了
You. What the hell was all that?
究竟怎样了
- I have it under control. - I'd hate to see you out of control.
- 皆在我掌握之中 - 你千万别失控
We don't have time for this. I'm getting off at Kyoto.
没时间说这个 我在京都站下车
He's not gonna check every compartment.
他不会搜索每节车厢
Yeah, well, I don't like trains.
总言之我不喜欢坐火车
Listen. Every man for himself.
各位各自保重
Hey, guys. Hey. How are you? How you doing, huh?
还好吗 在做什么
Good.  Okay, I guess.
- 安好 - 还行
Okay? Who's just okay? Is that you, James?
谁还行 是占仔吗
Yeah. When are you coming home, Dad?
爸爸 你几时回家
Well, I can't, sweetheart. I can't. Not for a while, remember?
我一时之间不能回家
Why?
为什么?
Look, I told you, I'm away because I'm working, right?
因为我要在这里工作
Grandma says you're never coming back.
祖母说你不会回来
Phillipa, is that you?
是菲丽吗
Put Grandma on the phone for me, will you?
让祖母听电话
She's shaking her head.
她不想同你聊
Well, just hope she's wrong about that.
总言之我会回家
Daddy?
爸爸
Yeah, James?
怎么啦 占仔
Is Mommy with you?
妈妈和你在一起吗
James, we talked about this.
占仔 别旧事重提
Mommy's not here anymore.
妈妈已不在世
Where?
去哪了
That's enough, kids. Say bye-bye.
孩子们 该挂电话了
Listen, I'm gonna send some presents with Grandpa, all right?
我会让外公捎带礼物给你们
And you be good, you be...
记住听话
- Our ride's on the roof. - Right.
- 我们的飞机在屋顶 - 好
Hey, are you okay?
没事吧
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine. Why?
没事 怎么?
Well, down in the dream, Mal showing up.
美颖又在梦中出现
Look, I'm, uh, sorry about your leg. Won't happen again.
拖累大家 甚感抱歉
- It's getting worse, isn't it? - One apology's all you're getting, all right?
- 情况越严重? - 我都道歉了
- Where's Nash? - He hasn't shown. You wanna wait?
- 阿立在哪 - 还没到 要等吗
We were supposed to deliver Saito's expansion plans...
两小时前就该向康博公司
...to Cobol Engineering two hours ago.
报告计划进展
By now, they know we failed. It's time we disappear.
他们现该知道我们失败 该逃命了
- Where you gonna go? - Buenos Aires.
- 你要去哪 - 布宜诺斯艾利斯
I can lie low there, maybe sniff out a job when things quiet down. You?
我先暂避风头 事后再谋生计 你呢
Stateside.
美国
Send my regards.
代我向家人问好
He sold you out. Thought to come to me and bargain for his life.
他出卖你们 全盘托出以求苟活
So I offer you the satisfaction.
给机会你们以手还手
It's not the way I deal with things.
这不合我处事原则
- What will you do with him? - Nothing.
- 你打算怎么处置他 - 没打算
But I can't speak for Cobol Engineering.
但我不担保康博公司会怎么处置你们
- What do you want from us? - Inception.
- 你想要我们做什么? - 植入意念
- Is it possible? - Of course not.
- 能做到吗 - 不可能
If you can steal an idea from someone's mind...
若能潜入梦境I取意识
...why can't you plant one there instead?
为何不能植入意念
Okay, here's me planting an idea in your head.
让我们给你植入意念
I say, "Don't think about elephants." What are you thinking about?
比如「别想大象」 你会联想到什么
Elephants.
大象
Right. But it's not your idea, because you know I gave it to you.
但这是我们给你的意念
The subject's mind can always trace the genesis of the idea.
人的意识往往会去探寻意念的源头
- True inspiration's impossible to fake. - That's not true.
- 无可能导入假的意念 - 不一定
- Can you do it? - Are you offering me a choice?
- 你能实现? - 若你帮我脱险
Because I can find my own way to square things with Cobol.
帮我避开康博公司的追杀
Then you do have a choice.
你似乎没有选择余地
Then I choose to leave, sir.
那我可选择不干
Tell the crew where you want to go.
告诉机务人员你们要去哪
Hey, Mr. Cobb.
好 高比先生
How would you like to go home?
想回家吗
To America. To your children.
回去美国 陪在孩子身边?
You can't fix that. No one can.
你没可能做到
- Just like inception. - Cobb, come on.
- 就像植入意念 - 快
- How complex is the idea? - Simple enough.
- 要植入的意念有多复杂 - 很简单
No idea is simple when you need to plant it in somebody else's mind.
要植入一个意念 没有简单一说
My main competitor is an old man in poor health.
我主要竞争对手是垂死的老翁
His son will soon inherit control of the corporation.
他儿子很快要继承公司
I need him to decide to break up his father's empire.
我要他解散他令尊的公司
- Cobb, we should walk away from this. - Hold on.
- 杜文 我们不要插手这事 - 稍等
If I were to do this, if I even could do it...
我帮你做事
...I'd need a guarantee.
但我需要证明
- How do I know you can deliver? - You don't.
- 证明你能帮我洗脱罪名 - 证明不到
But I can.
不过我可以保证
So do you want to take a leap of faith...
你是选择孤注一掷
...or become an old man, filled with regret...
抑或抱恨终身
...waiting to die alone?
直至终老?
Assemble your team, Mr. Cobb. And choose your people more wisely.
高比先生 组建团队 慎重选人
Look, I know how much you wanna go home.
我深知你归家心切
This can't be done.
但不可能植入意念
Yes, it can. Just have to go deep enough.
行的 只要潜梦够深
You don't know that.
何以得知
I've done it before.
我试过
Who'd you do it to?
你对谁动手
Why are we going to Paris?
为什么去巴黎
We're gonna need a new architect.
我们需要新的造梦师
You never did like your office, did you?
其实你从不喜欢待在办公室 对吧?
No space to think in that broom cupboard.
人太多就没法思考
Is it safe for you to be here?
待在这儿对你来说安全吗
Extradition between France and the United States...
官僚主义对法国和美国g的引渡条约
...is a bureaucratic nightmare, you know that.
根本没有办法
I think they might find a way to make it work in your case.
我觉得他们会想办法引渡你
Look, I, uh, brought these for you to give to the kids when you have a chance.
我买了些礼物 有机会你捎带给小孩
It'll take more than the occasional stuffed animal...
单凭送玩具
...to convince those children they still have a father.
就尽到为人父亲之责?
I'm just doing what I know. I'm doing what you taught me.
我只是做我应该做的 你亦是这样教我
I never taught you to be a thief.
我没有教子为贼
No, you taught me to navigate people's minds.
你教我操纵人的意识
But after what happened...
之后呢?
...there weren't a whole lot of legitimate ways for me to use that skill.
现在这种手法却被认为不合法
What are you doing here, Dom?
你前来做什么
I think I found a way home.
我想已找到归途
It's a job for some very, very powerful people.
我帮一个位高权重之人做事
People who I believe can fix my charges permanently.
他可以帮我撤销控罪
But I need your help.
但我需要你帮忙
You're here to corrupt one of my brightest and best.
你想来误我学生前程?
You know what I'm offering. Let them decide for themselves.
他们可以自行决定是否加入
- Money. - Not just money.
- 钱财 - 不只是钱财
You remember.
你心知肚明
It's the chance to build cathedrals, entire cities...
他们有机会建造教堂、城市
...things that never existed...
一系列不存在
...things that couldn't exist in the real world.
现实不存在的事物
So you want me to let someone else follow you into your fantasy?
你要我物色一个人与你潜入
They don't actually come into the dream.
他们不是真的进入梦空间
They just design the levels and teach them to the dreamers. That's all.
他们只是构建梦空间的层次和告诉做梦者
Design it yourself.
你自己不动手?
Mal won't let me.
美颖会阻止我
Come back to reality, Dom.
别痴人说梦
- Please. - Reality.
- 现实点 - 现实
Those kids, your grandchildren...
现实是你的孙儿
...they're waiting for their father to come back home. That's their reality.
正等待父亲归家
And this job, this last job, that's how I get there.
这项最后任务 事成便能回家
I would not be standing here if I knew any other way.
若有他法 亦不会苦苦哀求你
I need an architect who's as good as I was.
我需要个和我同等级数的造梦师
I've got somebody better.
有个比你还厉害
Ariadne?
爱莲?
I'd like you to meet Mr. Cobb.
认识下高比先生
Pleased to meet you.
好荣幸认识你
If you have a few moments, Mr. Cobb has a job offer he'd like to discuss with you.
若你有时间 高比先生想要你接一份差事
A work placement?
你有空缺
Not exactly.
不算是
I have a test for you.
先考验你
You're not gonna tell me anything first?
先告诉我工作内容
Before I describe the job, I have to know you can do it.
讲之前 我要了解你能否胜任
- Why? - It's not, strictly speaking, legal.
- 为什么 - 严格来说此工作不合法
You have two minutes to design a maze that it takes one minute to solve.
两分钟设计个需要一分钟破解的迷宫
Stop.
停
Again.
再来
You're gonna have to do better than that.
你可以做得更好
That's more like it.
挺像样
They say we only use a fraction of our brain's true potential.
当我们处于清醒状态时
Now, that's when we're awake.
我们只利用一小部分意识潜能
When we're asleep, our mind can do almost anything.
处于睡眠时 意识便能略有所展
Such as?
例如
Imagine you're designing a building. You consciously create each aspect.
想象你在设计楼宇 你有意识地设计每个细节
But sometimes, it feels like it's almost creating itself, if you know what I mean.
有时会觉得楼宇是一气呵成 明白吗
Yeah, like I'm discovering it.
就像在不断发现
Genuine inspiration, right?
发现真正的灵感 对吧?
Now, in a dream, our mind continuously does this.
梦中 我们的意识不停活动
We create and perceive our world simultaneously.
同时创造和认知我们的精神世界
And our mind does this so well that we don't even know it's happening.
过程如此畅顺 令人毫不知情
That allows us to get right in the middle of that process.
因此我们有机会趁机入侵
- How? - By taking over the creating part.
- 怎么入侵? - 我们主导构造梦空间
Now, this is where I need you.
所以才需要你
You create the world of the dream.
你创造梦空间
We bring the subject into that dream, and they fill it with their subconscious.
我们将目标带进来 令其迁移意识到此
How could I ever acquire enough detail to make them think that it's reality?
梦境如何设计才令他们相信置身现实
Well, dreams, they feel real while we're in them, right?
发梦时总觉得是真的 对吧?
It's only when we wake up that we realize something was actually strange.
梦醒时顿觉不妥
Let me ask you a question.
问你个问题
You never really remember the beginning of a dream, do you?
你不会记得梦是如何开始?
You always wind up right in the middle of what's going on.
你总是出现于梦进展的中部
I guess, yeah.
是
So how did we end up here?
那为什么我们会在这
Well, we just came from the, uh...
我们是从…
Think about it, Ariadne. How did you get here?
好好想想 你怎么到这的
Where are you right now?
这是哪里
We're dreaming?
我们在梦中?
You're in the middle of the workshop, sleeping.
其实你在工作室睡着了
This is your first lesson in shared dreaming. Stay calm.
这是共进梦空间的第一课 保持镇静
If it's just a dream, then why are you...?
若只是梦 那为什么你…
Because it's never just a dream, is it?
不止梦那么简单 对吧
And a face full of glass hurts like hell. When you're in it, it feels real.
当你面前充满碎片 如置身地狱 感觉亦真亦幻
That's why the military developed dream sharing.
这是军队研发的技术
It was a training program for soldiers to shoot, stab and strangle each other...
用来训练士兵射击、刺杀、束缚
...and then wake up.
等格斗技法
How did architects become involved?
造梦师的任务是什么?
Well, someone had to design the dreams, right?
我们需要有人来设计梦空间
Why don't you give us another five minutes?
我们再试一次五分钟的梦
Five minutes?
五分钟?
What...? We were talking for, like, at least an hour.
刚刚在梦里至少聊一小时
In a dream, your mind functions more quickly...
在梦中人脑运作迅速
...therefore time seems to feel more slow.
所以感觉时间过得较慢
Five minutes in the real world gives you an hour in the dream.
现实五分钟等于梦中一小时
Why don't you see what you can get up to in five minutes?
要不要试试五分钟内能做多少事
Almost everything else is here too.
大致差不多
Who are the people? - Projections of my subconscious.
- 这些人? - 我的潜意识投射影子
- Yours? - Yes.
- 你? - 是
Remember, you are the dreamer. You build this world.
你是造梦师 你创建这个梦境
I am the subject. My mind populates it.
我是目标人物 我的意识会迁移到此
You can literally talk to my subconscious.
你可以跟我的潜意识交流
That's one of the ways we extract information from the subject.
这是一种意识盗取的方法
How else do you do it?
你还能做什么?
By creating something secure, like a bank vault or a jail.
可建造某安全地方 银行保险库或监狱
The mind automatically fills it with information it's trying to protect.
意识会不知不觉将保密的信息放进去
- You understand? - Then you break in and steal it?
- 明白吗 - 然后你就入侵盗取
I guess I thought that the dream space would be all about the visual...
本以为梦空间与现实大致相似便可
...but it's more about the feel of it.
且料更要有令人现实感触般的感觉
My question is what happens when you start messing with the physics of it all?
若颠覆物理规则 会发生什么事?
It's something, isn't it?
神乎其技
Yes, it is.
是
Why are they all looking at me?
为什么他们都望着我
Because my subconscious feels that someone else is creating this world.
因我的潜意识察觉此梦空间是入侵者建造
The more you change things, the quicker the projections start to converge on you.
梦空间变化幅度越大 影子们就越会关注你
Converge?
关注?
They sense the foreign nature of the dreamer.
影子们察觉到入侵者
They attack, like white blood cells fighting an infection.
影子们便如白血球攻击病毒般攻击你
- What, they're gonna attack us? - No, no.
- 影子们要攻击我们 - 不是
Just you.
是攻击你
This is great, but I'm telling you, if you keep changing things like this...
好极 我告诫过你 继续改变梦空间
Jeez, mind telling your subconscious to take it easy?
叫你潜意识放松点
It's my subconscious. Remember? I can't control it.
那是潜意识 非人为控制
Very impressive.
神乎其技
I know this bridge. This place is real, isn't it?
我见过这座桥 真有此桥
Yeah, I cross it every day to get to the college.
我每日都穿过此桥上学
Never re-create places from your memory. Always imagine new places.
千万别利用真实记忆创造梦空间 要凭空想象
You draw from stuff you know, right?
但一般都从熟悉的事物开始创作
Only use details. A streetlamp or a phone booth. Never entire areas.
细节可用真实记忆填补 但别全盘照搬
- Why not? - Building a dream from your memory...
- 为什么不行? - 用真实记忆创造梦空间
...is the easiest way to lose your grasp on what's real and what is a dream.
极易令你真幻难分
- Is that what happened to you? - Listen to me.
- 你试过? - 告诫你
This has nothing to do with me, understand?
做好你的份内事
That why you need me to build your dreams?
所以才让我当你的造梦师
Hey, get off of her. Back up. Back up.
别动她 退后
- Cobb! Cobb! - Get off of her!
- 杜文 - 放开她
- Let me go! Let me go! - Mal!
- 放开我 - 美颖
- Mal! - Cobb! Wake me up!
- 美颖 - 杜文 清醒
- Wake me up! Wake me up! - No!
醒醒
- Mal, no! No! - Wake me up!
- 美颖 不要 - 我要醒
Hey, hey, hey. Look at me. You're okay. You're okay.
没事啦
- Hey. - Why wouldn't I wake up?
为什么我醒不过来
There was still time on the clock.
因校定的时间没到
You can't wake up from within the dream unless you die.
除非你在梦中身亡
- She'll need a totem.  What?
- 她需要个标记 - 什么东西
A totem, it's a small personal...
标记是…
That's some subconscious you've got on you, Cobb!
全拜你潜意识所赐
- She's a real charmer. - Oh.
那女人很凶
- I see you met Mrs. Cobb. - She's his wife?
- 你遇见了高比太太 - 是他内人
Yeah. So a totem. You need a small object, potentially heavy.
你需要标记 能帮你分辨梦境
Something you can have on you that no one else knows.
只有自己才知道其为何物
Like a coin?  No.
硬币?
It needs to be more unique than that. Like, this is a loaded die.
要独一无二 比如特制骰子
No, I can't let you touch it. That would defeat the purpose.
不能让你碰 不然就不起作用
See, only I know the balance and the weight of this particular loaded die.
只有我知道这骰子的平衡方式和重量
That way, when you look at your totem...
只要检查你的标记
...you know beyond a doubt that you're not in someone else's dream.
可以确定是不是在别人的梦里
I don't know if you can't see what's going on, or if you just don't want to...
不知道你是真不觉得还是假装不觉得
...but Cobb has some serious problems that he's tried to bury down there.
杜文有很严重的问题 他想要葬身潜意识
And I'm not about to just open my mind to someone like that.
我不允许这样的人进入我意识
She'll be back. I've never seen anyone pick it up that quickly before.
她会回来 爱莲很有天赋
Reality's not gonna be enough for her now, and when she comes back...
当现实无法满足她 便会回来
When she comes back, you're gonna have her building mazes.
当她回来 你得教她建迷宫
- Where are you gonna be? - I gotta go visit Eames.
- 你去哪 - 我要拜访奕祠
Eames? No, he's in Mombasa. It's Cobol's back yard.
奕祠? 他在蒙巴萨 是康柏公司的据点
It's a necessary risk.
值得冒险
- Well, there's plenty of good thieves. - We don't just need a thief.
- 有很多厉害的盗梦者 - 不止需要盗梦者
We need a forger.
我们需要伪变术士
Rub them together all you want, they're not gonna breed.
玩这个很难有赚
You never know.
说不准
I'm gonna get you a drink.
请你喝杯
You're buying.
好
- Your spelling hasn't improved. - Piss off.
- 你的拼写还是没进步 - 收声
How's your handwriting?
书写呢
- It's versatile. - Good.
- 没人能及 - 好
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Inception.
植入意念
Now, before you bother telling me it's impossible, let me...
不要跟我说不可能
No, it's perfectly possible. It's just bloody difficult.
万事皆有可能 只是很难成功
Interesting. Because Arthur keeps telling me it can't be done.
有意思 缘因雅迪坚持认为不可能
Hmm. Arthur. You still working with that stick in the mud?
雅迪?你还和他共事?
He is good at what he does, right?
他精于所善 不是吗?
Oh, he's the best, but he has no imagination.
不错 就是没有想象力
Not like you.
不像你
Listen, if you're gonna perform inception, you need imagination.
若要植入意念 需要有想象力
Let me ask you something. Have you done it before?
你以前做过植入意念吗
We tried it. Uh, we got the idea in place, but it didn't take.
我们试过将意念植进去 但目标没接受
- You didn't plant it deep enough? - No, it's not just about depth.
- 植入不够深? - 不是深度的问题
You need the simplest version of the idea...
所植入到意念信息要够简单
...in order for it to grow naturally in your subject's mind. It's a subtle art.
自然而然令目标接受此意念
So, what is this idea that you need to plant?
你要植入的是什么意念
We need the heir of a major corporation to dissolve his father's empire.
我们要让个继承人解散其尊的家业
Right there you have various political motivations...
你可以找一堆政治动机
...and anti-monopolistic sentiments and so forth.
还有反垄断观点之类
But all of that stuff, it's, um...
不过一切都
It's really at the mercy of your subject's prejudice, you see?
按照目标个人喜好而定
What you have to do is start at the absolute basic.
从最基本动手
Which is what?
最基本?
The relationship with the father.
父子关系
- Do you have a chemist? - No, not yet.
- 有药剂师吗? - 还没找到
Right. Okay, well, there's a man here, Yusuf.
我有人选推荐 佑沭
He, uh, formulates his own versions of the compounds.
他有很多独门药剂秘方
Why don't you take me there?
快引荐我
Once you've lost your tail. The man at the bar.
先甩掉那个跟踪你的人
Cobol Engineering.
康博公司派来的
That price on my head, was that dead or alive?
追缉令是留命还是留尸
Don't remember. Let's see if he starts shooting.
忘了 不知道会不会开枪
Run interference. I'll meet you downstairs in the bar in, say, uh, half an hour?
你负责引开他们的注意力 半小时后在楼下酒吧会合
- Back here? - This is the last place they'd suspect.
- 回到这里? - 最危险之地亦是最安全
All right.
好
Freddy. Freddy Simmonds.
非迪 你是非迪?
My God, it's you, isn't it?
肯定是你
No, it isn't you.
我认错人
Not dreaming now, are you?
你以为仍在梦空间啊
Get him!
捉住他
There!
这里
Care for a lift, Mr. Cobb?
上车 杜文
- What are you doing in Mombasa? - I'm here to protect my investment.
- 你来蒙巴萨干嘛 - 我来保护我的投资
Ah. So this is your idea of losing a tail, huh?
你就是用此法甩掉跟尾?
Different tail.
简直死缠烂打
Cobb said you'd be back.
杜文说你回来
- I tried not to come, but... - But there's nothing quite like it.
- 我也想不来 但… - 但其他没有如此刺激
It's just...
我只是
...pure creation.
纯粹创建
Shall we take a look at some paradoxical architecture?
我们来看看一些似非而是的建筑物
You're gonna have to master a few tricks...
若你要建立三个完整层次的梦空间
...if you're gonna build three complete dream levels. Excuse me.
你须要掌握一些窍门
What kind of tricks?
什么窍门
In a dream, you can cheat architecture into impossible shapes.
在梦空间 你可天马行空设计建筑物
That lets you create closed loops, like the Penrose Steps.
以于创造封闭式循环 如彭罗斯楼梯
The infinite staircase.
无尽之阶
See?
清楚吗
Paradox.
似非而是
So a closed loop like that...
封闭式循环可以
...will help you disguise the boundaries of the dream you create.
助你隐藏梦空间的边境
But how big do these levels have to be?
要弄多大的梦空间
It could be anything from the floor of a building to an entire city.
可以小如一层楼宇 大如整个城市
They have to be complicated enough that we can hide from the projections.
但是结构需要复杂 才能令我们避开意识影子
- A maze? - Right, a maze.
- 像迷宫? - 像个迷宫
And the better the maze...
迷宫越复杂
Then the longer we have before the projections catch us?
便能有更长时间避开影子攻击
Exactly.
没错
- My subconscious seems polite enough. - Ha, ha. You wait, they'll turn ugly.
- 我潜意识看起来挺镇静 - 好话莫早说
No one likes to feel someone else messing around in their mind.
没人喜欢潜意识被入侵
Cobb can't build anymore, can he?
杜文无法再建造梦空间?
I don't know if he can't, but he won't.
关键是他不想
He thinks it's safer if he doesn't know the layouts.
他觉得不知道梦空间布局反而对大家好
Why?
为什么
He won't tell me. But I think it's Mal.
他没说 我猜是基于美颖的缘故
- His ex-wife? - No, not his ex.
- 他前妻? - 不是前妻
- They're still together? - No.
他们至今还一起?
No, she's dead.
美颖已经不在人世
What you see in there is just his projection of her.
你那时看到的 只是个投射影子
What was she like in real life?
她在现实中是个什么样的人
She was lovely.
很可爱
You are seeking a chemist?  Yes.
你在物色药剂师?
To formulate compounds for a job?
配制任务要用到的药物?
And to go into the field with us.
还要我们同起进入梦空间
No, I rarely go into the field, Mr. Cobb.
我不会进入梦空间
Well, we'd need you there to tailor compounds specific to our needs.
需实地考察才能配置出我们想要的药剂
- Which are? - Great depth.
- 实地考察? - 深度梦空间
A dream within a dream? Two levels?
梦中梦?两层?
Three.
三层
Not possible. That many dreams within dreams is too unstable.
如斯多层次 梦空间会不稳定
It is possible. You just have to add a sedative.
只要有镇静剂便成事
A powerful sedative.
应该是强力镇静剂
- How many team members? - Five.
- 有多少个组员 - 五个
Six.
六个
The only way to know you've done the job is if I go in with you.
我也要进去 以便验收任务
There's no room for tourists on a job like this, Mr. Saito.
这项任务不适合你参与
This time, it seems there is.
就这样决定
This, I think, is a good place to start. I use it every day.
我每天都在用这个 效果不错
What for? - Here, I'll show you.
- 你用来干嘛 - 来看看
Perhaps you will not want to see.
还是不看为妙
After you.
请带路
Ten. Twelve. All connected. Bloody hell.
十、十二个 都连在一起
They come every day to share the dream.
他们每日都来此共进梦空间
You see? Very stable.
看 梦空间很稳定
- How long do they dream for?  Three, four hours, each day.
- 他们要做多久梦 - 每日三、四小时
In dream time?
梦空间时间呢?
With this compound? About 40 hours, each and every day.
有这种配方 大概每日四十小时
- Why do they do it?  Tell him, Mr. Cobb.
- 他们为什么做这个 - 杜文 告诉他
After a while, it becomes the only way you can dream.
持之以恒的话 便只能以此方式做梦
Do you still dream, Mr. Cobb?
你还会做梦吗 高比先生
- They come here every day to sleep?  No.
- 他们每天来此入睡 - 不是
They come to be woken up.
来此是为等待被唤醒
The dream has become their reality.
梦已成为他们的现实世界
Who are you to say otherwise, sir?
所言不虚吧?
Let's see what you can do.
还是亲身体验为实
You know how to find me.
你知道如何找到我
You know what you have to do.
你知道应该如何是好
Sharp, no?
满意吧
Are you all right, Mr. Cobb?
高比先生 没事吧
Yeah, yeah. Everything's just fine.
没事
Robert Fischer, heir to the Fischer Morrow energy conglomerate.
路裴・非榭  非榭能源公司的继承人
What's your problem with this Mr. Fischer?
你与这位非榭先生有什么过节?
That's not your concern.
不关你事
Mr. Saito, this isn't your typical corporate espionage.
齐藤先生 这不是你常用的商业间谍手段
You asked me for inception.
是你要求我植入意念
I do hope you understand the gravity of that request.
你要明白实行要求的后果
Now, the seed that we plant in this man's mind will grow into an idea.
一旦在人的思想播种 便会发展为意念
This idea will define him.
此意念会左右他
It may come to change...
会改变…
Well, it may come to change everything about him.
可能会改变他的一生
We're the last company standing between them and total energy dominance.
我司是唯一一间阻挡非榭能源公司垄断能源
And we can no longer compete.
不过我司以无抵抗之力
Soon, they'll control the energy supply of half the world.
很快 非榭能源公司 会控制半个世界的能源供应
In effect, they become a new superpower.
最终非榭能源公司会成为大赢家
The world needs Robert Fischer to change his mind.
总言之要令路裴改变想法
That's where we come in.
所以才需要我们
How is Robert Fischer's relationship with his father?
路裴与其父的关系如何
Rumor is the relationship is quite complicated.
传闻话关系甚为复杂
Well, we can't work based solely on rumor, can we?
传闻不足为信
Can you get me access to this man here? Browning.
有办法帮我接近布宁吗
Fischer Senior's right-hand man. Fischer Junior's godfather.
路裴其父的得力助手 亦是路裴的教父
It should be possible, if you can get the right references.
应该可以 只要弄到有力的推荐书
References are something of a specialty for me, Mr. Saito.
弄推荐书是我专长
I'm not smelling settlement here. Take them down.
我不能对此案一笑置之 告倒他们
Mr. Browning...
布宁先生
...Maurice Fischer's policy is always one of avoiding litigation.
麦利・非榭的政策倾向于回避诉讼
Well, shall we voice your concerns with Maurice directly?
要不要直接跟麦利先生面谈
Not sure that's necessary.
无此必要
No, no, no. I think we should.
我觉得有必要
How is he?
他怎样了
I don't want to bother him unnecessarily, but...
若无必要 我不想打扰他
Robert, I told you keep out the damn... Wait. So do it. Get...
路裴 我告诫你不要来这里
Never, never. Never do the same as I asked.
我没下令不准让他来
Leave that.
离开
Here.
这里
Must be a cherished memory of his.
那定是他宝贵的回忆
I put it beside his bed. He hasn't even noticed.
我摆放在他床边 他却无心暇顾
Robert...
路裴
...we need to talk about a power of attorney.
我们要谈谈授权书的问题
- I know this is hard, but it's imperative... - Not now, Uncle Peter.
- 虽然很难决定 但势在必行 - 现在不行
The vultures are circling.
秃鹰虎视眈眈
And the sicker Maurice Fischer becomes, the more powerful Peter Browning becomes.
自从麦利病床 彼得・布宁的权力日益增多
I've had ample opportunity to observe Browning...
我已观察多日
... and adopt his physical presence, study his mannerisms, and so on and so forth.
习惯他的外貌特征 行为举止等
So now in the first layer of the dream, I can impersonate Browning.
因此梦空间第一层 我会伪装成彼得
And suggest concepts to Fischer's conscious mind.
对路裴的意识稍作暗示
Then, when we take him a level deeper...
接着再带他进第二层
...his own projection of Browning should feed that right back to him.
他潜意识映射出的彼得会如我们所料行动
So he gives himself the idea.
总言之他自己为自己植入意念
Precisely. That's the only way it will stick. It has to seem self-generated.
没错 让他自然而然有此意念
Eames, I am impressed.
奕祠 简直叹为观止
Your condescension, as always, is much appreciated, Arthur, thank you.
你所谓的屈尊俯就亦令我叹为观止
Were you going under on your own?
你刚刚进入自己的梦空间?
No, no, I was just, uh, running some experiments.
不 我只是在做些实验
I didn't realize anyone was here, so...
我不知道还有人在这
Yeah, I was just... I was working on my totem, actually.
我刚才在做我的标记
Here, let me take a look.
让我看看
So you're learning, huh?
学得不错
An elegant solution for keeping track of reality.
用标记来析别梦空间是个很好的方法
- Was it your idea? - No, it was, uh...
- 你想出来的? - 不
It was Mal's, actually. This...
是美颖想出来的
This one was hers. She would spin it in the dream and it would never topple.
这个是她的标记 梦中旋转永不倒
Just spin and spin.
永无止境地旋转
Arthur told me she passed away.
雅迪告知我 她已不在人世
How are the mazes coming along?
迷宫设计得如何
Each level relates to the part of the subject's subconscious...
梦空间每层都紧紧关联
...that we are trying to access.
我们将入侵目标的那部份潜意识
So I'm making the bottom level a hospital, so Fischer will bring his father.
最低那层是医院 路裴会带其父到来
You know, l... Actually, I have a question about this layout.
不过我对此布局心存怀疑
No, no, no. Don't show me specifics. Only the dreamer should know the layout.
别告诉我细节 自己知道就行
Why is that so important?
为什么
In case one of us brings in our projections.
以防我们中有人将自己的潜意识影子带进来
We don't want them knowing the details of the maze.
不能让他们知道迷宫的细节
You mean in case you bring Mal in.
你深怕美颖会进来?
You can't keep her out, can you?
你控制不了她 对不
- Right. - You can't build...
- 对 - 你无法筑梦
...because if you know the maze, then she knows it.
是因你知道布局 美颖也会知道
Well, she'd sabotage the whole operation.
会破坏全局
- Cobb, do the others know? - No. No, they don't.
- 杜文 其他人知道吗 - 他们不知道
You've gotta warn them if this is getting worse.
你定要提醒他们 以免不可收拾
No one said it's getting worse.
不会不可收拾
I need to get home. That's all I care about right now.
当务之急 是我要回家
Why can't you go home?
为什么你不能回家
Because they think I killed her.
因为他们认为我杀了她
- Thank you. - For what?
- 谢谢 - 干嘛
For not asking whether I did.
没问我是否杀了她
"I will split up my father's empire."
我要摧毁家父的家业
Now, this is obviously an idea that Robert himself would choose to reject...
很明显 路裴不会接受这个意念
...which is why we need to plant it deep in his subconscious.
我们要将意念植入到潜意识深处
The subconscious is motivated by emotion, right? Not reason.
潜意识是由情感控制 而非理智?
We need to find a way to translate this into an emotional concept.
我们要将此意念情感化
How do you translate business strategy into emotion?
怎样将此意念情感化
That's what we're here to figure out. Robert's relationship with his father...
问题关键在于此 至少我们得知
...is stressed, to say the least. - Can we run with that?
- 路裴与其父关系紧张 - 何不利用这点
We suggest breaking up his father's company as a "screw you" to the old man.
我们暗示他摧毁祖业 借以打击其父
No, because I think positive emotion trumps negative emotion every time.
不行 我认为负面情感远不及正面情感
We all yearn for reconciliation, for catharsis.
应该让他们和解如好
We need Robert Fischer to have a positive emotional reaction to all this.
继而令路裴顿悟出此意念
All right, well, try this. Um...
值得一试
"My father accepts that I want to create for myself, not follow in his footsteps."
「家父接纳我 同时我要另创天地 而非承袭父荫」
That might work.
可能行得通
Might? We're gonna need to do a little better than "might."
可能?须付诸可行
Thank you for your contribution, Arthur.
有劳高见 雅迪
Forgive me for wanting a little specificity, Eames.
我只是想知道具体点
Specificity?
具体点
Inception's not about being specific.
不需要植入很具体的意念
When we get inside his mind, we're gonna have to work with what we find.
当我们入侵他意识后 再见机行事
On the top level, we open up his relationship with his father...
在第一层 我们坦诚见谈父子关系
...and say, "I will not follow in my father's footsteps."
「我不会承袭父荫」
Then the next level down, we feed him, "I will create something for myself."
第二层 我们播下「我要另创天地」
Then, by the time we hit the bottom level, we bring out the big guns.
继而最后一层 使出杀手锏
- "My father doesn't want me to be him."  Exactly.
- 「家尊不愿我效他所为」 - 妙极
Three layers down, the dreams are gonna collapse with the slightest disturbance.
若有一点动静 三层梦空间便会崩毁
Sedation.
镇静剂
For sleep stable enough to create three layers of dreaming...
创造三层梦空间 前提是稳定睡眠状态
...we'll have to combine it with an extremely powerful sedative.
我们需要强力镇静剂
Good night.
晚安
The compound we'll be using to share the dream...
用来共进梦空间的配方
... creates a clear connection between dreamers...
有助增强做梦者之间的联系
...whilst accelerating brain function. - In other words, more time on each level.
- 同时加速脑部运作 - 总言之 每层的时间会变长
Brain function in the dream will be about 20 times normal.
梦空间的脑部运作比平时约快廿倍
And when you enter a dream within that dream, the effect is compounded.
当你进入梦中梦 运作速度亦倍增
It's three dreams, that's 10 hours times 20...
三层梦 所以是平时十小时乘以廿…
Math was never my strong subject. How much time is that?
我不擅长数数 究竟多久
It's a week, the first level down.
第一层约一星期
Six months the second level down, and the third level...
第二层约六个月 至于第三层
That's 10 years.
约十年
Who'd wanna be stuck in a dream for 10 years?
谁会想困在梦空间十年?
Depends on the dream.
那要看是什么梦
So once we've made the plant, how do we get out?
一旦成功植入 如何撤离梦空间
I'm hoping you have something more elegant than shooting me in the head.
有没有比打爆头更文雅的方法
- A kick. - What's a kick?
- 堕醒 - 什么是堕醒
This, Ariadne, would be a kick.
爱莲 这就是堕醒
It's that feeling of falling you get that jolts you awake.
坠落摇晃直到清醒
- Snaps you out of the dream. - We gonna feel a kick with this sedation?
- 瞬间醒梦 - 服用镇静剂 堕醒仍有效吗?
That's the clever part.
关键所在
I customized the sedative to leave inner-ear function unimpaired.
我特制的镇静剂不会削弱听觉功能
That way, however deep the sleep, the sleeper still feels falling.
无论如斯好睡 亦可感受到坠落感
Or tipping.
或者是翻倒
The trick is to synchronize a kick that can penetrate all three levels.
实施堕醒同步化三层梦空间
We could use a musical countdown to synchronize the different kicks.
可用音乐来倒计不同层次的堕醒
He hasn't got any surgery scheduled, no dental, nothing.
他最近没有预约手术 甚至预约牙医也没有
Wasn't he supposed to have a knee operation?
他本来不是要做膝关节手术?
Nothing. Nothing that they'll put him under for, anyway. And we need...
找不到任何机会令他昏睡
We need at least a good 10 hours.
我们至少需要十小时
Sydney to Los Angeles.
悉尼飞往洛杉矶
One of the longest flights in the world. He makes it every two weeks.
世上最长航线之一 他每两周要来回一次
He must be flying private, then.
他一定乘坐私人飞机
Not if there were unexpected maintenance with his plane.
可以安排他的专机进行维修
It would have to be a 747. - Why's that?
- 最好他乘坐波音747 - 为什么
On a 747, the pilot's up top...
波音747的驾驶舱在上层
...the first-class cabin's in the nose, so no one would walk through.
头等舱在其后面 闲杂人不得经过
You'd have to buy out the entire cabin and the first-class flight attendant.
要买通机舱员工 包下头等舱
I bought the airline.
我买下整个航空公司
It seemed neater.
何足挂齿
Well, looks like we have our 10 hours.
那我们有十小时时间
Ariadne? Terrific work, by the way.
爱莲 干得好
You know how to find me.
你深知如何找我
You know what you have to do.
你深知如何是好
You remember when you asked me to marry you?
仍记得你求婚时的话语吗
Of course I do.
仍记得
You said you had a dream.
你说你梦见
That we'd grow old together.
梦见我们白头偕老
And we can.
我们皆可实现
You shouldn't be here.
你不该在这
Just wanted to see what kind of tests you're doing on your own every night.
我只想知道你每晚独在这做什么实验
- This has nothing to do with you. - This has everything to do with me.
- 不关你事 - 当然关我事
- You've asked me to share dreams with you. - Not these. These are my dreams.
- 是你叫我跟你共进梦空间 - 不是这些 这些是我自己的梦
Why do you do this to yourself?
为何如斯困磨自己?
It's the only way I can still dream.
唯有此法我才能做梦
Why is it so important to dream?
作梦有这么重要吗
In my dreams, we're still together.
只有在梦中我们才在一起
These aren't just dreams.
并非梦般简单
These are memories. And you said never to use memories.
这是你的记忆 你说过永不要用真实记忆创造梦空间
I know I did.
我明白
You're trying to keep her alive. You can't let her go.
你接受不到事实 你对她念念不忘
You don't understand. These are moments I regret.
你永不感受到 如斯时刻令我后悔莫及
They're memories that I have to change.
如斯回忆令我欲变难求
Well, what's down there that you regret?
下面是?
Listen, there's only one thing you need to understand about me.
你只需要明白一件事
This is your house?
这是你家?
Mine and Mal's, yes.
我和美颖的家
Where is she?
她在哪
She's already gone.
她已经走
That's my son, James.
这是我儿子 占仔
He's digging for something, maybe a worm.
他总喜欢掘蚯蚓之类
That's Phillipa.
这是菲丽
I thought about calling out to them...
我总想和他们
...so they'd turn and smile and I could see...
齐序天伦之乐
...those beautiful faces of theirs, but it's all too late.
可惜为时已晚
Right now or never, Cobb.
此时不走更待何时
Then I start to panic.
此时我开始心乱
I realize I'm gonna regret this moment...
最后一次再序天伦之乐
...that I need to see their faces one last time.
否则我会遗恨终生
James! Phillipa! Come on in!
占仔 菲丽 过来
But the moment's past.
时过境迁
And whatever I do, I can't change this moment.
纵使力挽狂澜 亦是无法挽回
As I'm about to call out to them...
当我呼叫他们之际
...they run away.
他们却远离我
If I'm ever gonna see their faces again, I've gotta get back home.
若重拾旧景 我誓要回家
The real world.
而非凭梦牵挂
What are you doing here?
你在这干嘛
My name is...
我是
I know who you are. What are you doing here?
我认识你 但你在干嘛
I'm just trying to understand.
我只是想明白
How could you understand?
你无法明白
Do you know what it is to be a lover?
明白何为两情相悦吗
To be half of a whole?
明白何为命里佳人吗
No.
不明白
I'll tell you a riddle.
猜个谜语
You're waiting for a train.
你等待一列火车
A train that will take you far away.
火车将带你远去他方
You know where you hope this train will take you...
你深知前去何方
...but you don't know for sure.
同时你亦忧虑能否到达
But it doesn't matter.
不过无关紧要
How can it not matter to you where that train will take you?
为何不著紧前往何方?
Because you'll be together.
彼此相聚已胜一切
How could you bring her here, Dom? - What is this place?
- 杜文 为什么她会在这 - 这是哪
This is a hotel suite where we used to spend our anniversary.
这是我们旧时庆祝结婚纪念日的酒店套房
What happened here?
这里发生过什么
You promised! You promised we'd be together!
你说过我们会长厢思守
Please, I need you to stay here just for now!
请你暂时留守于此
You said we'd be together! You said we'd grow old together!
你说我们要执子之手  与子偕老
I'll come back for you. I promise.
我会回来找你
Do you think you can just build a prison of memories to lock her in?
你真认为建个记忆监狱能关住她?
Do you really think that that's gonna contain her?
你真认为这样能困住她
It's time.
是时候
Maurice Fischer just died in Sydney.
麦利・非榭刚在悉尼过逝
- When's the funeral? - Thursday. In Los Angeles.
- 几时举行葬礼 - 星期二 于洛杉矶
Robert should accompany the body no later than Tuesday. We should move.
路裴最迟星期二要去送葬 我们要行动
All right.
好极
- Cobb, I'm coming with you. - I promised Miles. No.
- 我陪同你去 - 不行
The team needs someone who understands what you're struggling with.
队中得有人知道你的处境
And it doesn't have to be me...
不一定非我不可
...but then you have to show Arthur what I just saw.
你亦可以告知雅迪一切
Get us another seat on the plane.
再安插个座位
If I get on this plane and you don't honor our agreement...
若我登上航班 你又不承诺协定
...when we land, I go to jail for the rest of my life.
登陆后 我就要到监狱度过余生
Complete the job en route...
只要完成任务
...I make one phone call from the plane...
我一声令下
...you have no trouble getting through Immigration.
你就可以顺利入境
- I'm sorry. - Oh, yeah, absolutely.
- 借过 - 失礼晒
Thank you.
有劳
Excuse me, I think this is yours? You must have dropped it.
是不是您的 应该是你掉的
FLIGHT  Would you care for a drink?
想喝点什么吗
Oh. Water, please.
来杯水
Oh, um, same, please.
我也是
Thank you.
谢谢
You know, I couldn't help but notice...
真没法不注意到
...but you wouldn't happen to be related to the Maurice Fischer, would you?
你是否是麦利・非榭的亲眷
Yes, he, um...
是
He was my father.
他是我家尊
Well, he was a very inspiring figure. I'm sorry for your loss.
他值万人敬仰 节哀顺便
- Here you go. - Thank you.
- 给 - 谢谢
To your father.
敬令尊
May he rest in peace, huh?
入土为安
- Couldn't have peed before you went under? - Sorry.
- 入梦前就应该如厕 - 抱歉
Bit too much free champagne before takeoff?
起飞前香槟喝太多
Ha, ha, bloody ha.
所言甚是
We know he's gonna be looking for a taxi in this weather.
这种天气他肯定要找出租车
- Asshole! Hey, man, why don't you try...? - Walk away.
- 蠢材 再来一次试试 - 走开
All right. Taxi. Thank you.
好极 出租车 有劳
All right, Third and Market. Snappy.
第三街和汶克路交汇处 快
- What are you doing? - Sorry, I thought it was free.
- 你干嘛 - 抱歉 我还以为空车
- It's not. - Maybe we could share.
- 不是 - 或许我们一起坐
Maybe not. Can you pull over and get this...?
麻烦靠边停车…
Great.
妙极
Come on.
快
There's $500 in there. The wallet's worth more than that.
这有500块 我钱包还更值钱
You might at least drop me at my stop.
至少送我到站
I'm afraid that it doesn't...
恐怕…
- Cover him!  Down! Down now!
- 掩护他 - 快趴下
What the hell is going on?
究竟发生什么事
This wasn't in the design.
我没设计这些
Cobb?
杜文
Get him!
干掉他
Are you all right?
没事吧
Yeah, I'm okay. I'm okay.
我没事
Fischer's okay, unless he gets carsick.
路裴没事 除非他晕车
Saito?
齐藤?
Get Fischer in the back room now.
把路裴关到后屋
- Get him in the back room. Move.  What the hell happened?
- 关到后屋 - 究竟发生什么事
Has he been shot? Is he dying?
他中枪?不会死吧?
I don't know. - Jesus Christ.
- 我不知道
What happened to you? - Blocked by a freight train.
- 你们遇到什么事了 - 被火车堵住了
Why put a train in a downtown intersection?
干嘛在市中心放辆火车
- I didn't.  Where'd it come from?
- 我没有 - 那它从哪来
Why the hell were we ambushed?
我们怎么会被袭击
Those were not normal projections. They'd been trained, for God's sakes.
他们绝非普通的影子 个个训练有素
- How could he be trained? - Fischer's had an extractor...
- 他怎会受过防御训练? - 路裴让盗梦者教他意识防卫
...teach his subconscious to defend itself, so his subconscious is militarized.
所以他有潜意识守护者
It should've shown in the research.
为什么调查时没发现
Why the hell didn't it? - Calm down.
- 为什么没发现 - 冷静
Don't tell me to calm down!
我简直冷静不下
This was your job, goddamn it! This was your responsibility!
这是你的本分事
You were meant to check Fischer's background!
你理应调查清楚
- We are not prepared for this! - We have dealt with sub-security before!
- 我们不知所措 - 之前也遇过类似
We'll be more careful and we're gonna be fine!
万事要步步为营
This was not a part of the plan! He's dying.
这并不在计划内 他快要死
Put him out his misery.
让他醒过来吧
- No, don't do that! Don't do that. - Cobb, hey, hey.
不要
He's in agony. I'm waking him up.
他很痛苦 我要唤醒他
No. It won't wake him up.
没用的
What do you mean, it won't wake him up? When we die in a dream, we wake up.
什么意思 在梦空间死亡便能苏醒
Not from this.
这次不会
We're too heavily sedated to wake up that way.
我们处于极度安稳沉睡状态
Right. So, what happens when we die?
那在梦空间死亡会怎样
- We drop into limbo. - Are you serious?
- 会掉入潜意识边缘 - 说真的?
- Limbo?  Unconstructed dream space.
- 潜意识边缘? - 意识混沌的空间
Well, what the hell is down there? - Just raw, infinite subconscious.
- 那里有什么 - 原始无尽的潜意识
Nothing is down there, except for what might have been left behind...
那里只有曾被困住的人
...by anyone sharing the dream who's been trapped there before.
所遗留下来的意识
Which, in our case, is just you.
看来就你去过
- How long could we be stuck?  Can't even think about...
- 我们会被困多久 - 药效失效前
...trying to escape until the sedation... - How long?
- 根本无望离开 - 多久
Decades. It could be infinite. Ask him, he's the one who's been there.
几十年 或许永远 问他 他去过
Let's get him upstairs.
抬他上楼
Great.
好极
Thank you.
多得你
So now we're trapped in Fischer's mind, battling his own private army.
现在我们困在路裴的梦空间 兼进行枪战
And if we get killed...
若果我们身亡
...we'll be lost in limbo till our brains turn to scrambled egg, hmm?
我们将迷失潜意识边缘直至消失 对吧
Someone got first aid?
有人懂得抢救
- You knew these risks and didn't tell us? - There weren't meant to be risks.
- 你明知有风险却不告诉我们 - 本来不会有风险
- I didn't know we'd be dealing with gunfire. - You had no right.
- 我怎料到会有枪战　 - 你应该事先告知
This was the only way to go three layers deep.
只有这样才能潜入三层梦空间
You knew about this and went along with it?
你知道这些还跟他一起来
I trusted him.
我对他有信心
When? When he promised you half his share?
他答应给你一半酬劳?
No. His whole share. Besides, he said he'd done it before.
是给全部 他以前也试过
What, with Mal? Because that worked so good?
以前和美颖试过?那次进展很顺利?
That has nothing to do with it. I did what I had to to get to my children.
两者没关系 我只是一心想见孩子
You led us into a war zone with no way out?
你令我们身陷险境
There is a way out. We continue on with the job, and we do it as fast as possible...
还有办法 我们尽快完成任务
...and we get out using the kick, just like before.
接而如之前般用堕醒方法返回
Forget it. We go any deeper, we just raise the stakes.
算了 我们走得越深 危险便越大
I am sitting this one out on this level.
我情愿留在这一层
Fischer's security is surrounding this place.
路裴的意识守护者已包围这里
Ten hours of flight time is a week at this level.
这一层的一个星期等于十小时飞行时间
That means each and every one of us will be killed. That I can guarantee you.
这意味着我们难逃被杀
We have no other choice but to continue on and do it as fast as possible.
唯有尽快完成任务
Downwards is the only way forwards.
唯今之计就是继续任务
Get ready.
准备
You, come on. Let's go shake him up.
你跟着来 把他弄醒
I'm insured against kidnapping for up to 10 million.
我投了一千万买绑架保险
- This should be very simple.  Shut up! It won't be.
- 应该很容易得手 - 闭嘴
In your father's office, below the bookshelves...
令尊办公室书架下面
...is his personal safe. We need the combination.
有个私人保险箱 我们需要密码
I don't know any safe.
我不清楚
That doesn't mean you don't know the combination.
那不代表你不知道密码
Tell us what it is.
告诉我们密码
I don't know.
我不知道
We have it on good authority you do know.
有消息来源说你知道
Yeah? Whose authority?
消息来源?
- Five hundred dollars, this cost.  What's inside it?
- 这东西值五百美元 - 里面有什么
Cash, cards, ID. And this.
现金 信用卡 身份证 还有这个
Useful?
有用吗
Maybe.
可能
You're on. You've got an hour.
轮到你 有一小时时间
An hour?
一小时?
I was supposed to have all night to crack this.
我应该有整晚的时间
And Saito wasn't supposed to be shot in the chest.
齐藤也不该胸口中枪
You've got one hour, now get us something useful, please.
只有一小时套料
- What's that? - Good authority.
- 怎么回事 - 消息来源
Uncle Peter.
彼得叔叔
Just make them stop.
置停他们
- The combination. - I don't know it.
- 密码 - 我不知道
- Why does Browning say you do? - I don't know.
- 那为什么你叔叔说你知道? - 我不知道
Just let me talk to him and I'll find out.
让我跟他谈谈 我就能知道
You have one hour. Start talking.
一个小时 只许谈话
You all right?
你没事吧
Those bastards have had at me for two days.
这帮混蛋囚禁我两天
They have someone with access to your father's office.
他们有同党能出入令尊办公室
- They're trying to open his safe. - Yeah.
他们想要打开保险箱
They thought I'd know the combination, but I don't know it.
他们以为我知道密码
- Yeah, well, neither do I, so... - What?
- 我也不知道 - 什么
Maurice told me that when he passed, you were the only one able to open it.
令尊说当他离世后 便只有你能打开
No, he never gave me any combination.
他从没告诉过我什么密码
Maybe he did. I mean, maybe you just didn't know it was a combination.
或许他说过 你只是不知那是密码
Well, what, then?
那会是什么
I don't know, some meaningful combination of numbers...
根据你和令尊相处所得
...based on your experiences with Maurice.
或许是有意义的数字组合
We didn't have very many, uh, meaningful experiences together.
我们根本没怎么相处过
Perhaps after your mother died.
也许在令堂离世后
After my mother died, you know what he told me?
家母离世后 你知道他说什么
"Robert, there's really nothing to be said."
路裴 我简直不知如何是好
Oh, well, he was bad with emotion.
他不善表达情感
I was 11, Uncle Peter.
那时我仅十一岁 彼得叔叔
- How's he doing? - He's in a lot of pain.
- 他怎么样 - 他很痛苦
When we get down to the lower levels, the pain will be less intense.
待进入下一层 痛苦会减轻些
And if he dies?
万一他死了
Worst-case scenario?
最坏情况?
When he wakes up, his mind is completely gone.
醒来后 意识全无
Cobb, I'll still honor the arrangement.
高比先生 我仍会遵守协定
I appreciate that, Saito.
我相信你
But when you wake up, you won't even remember that we had an arrangement.
但等你梦醒 你根本不会记得协定
Limbo is gonna become your reality.
你会把潜意识边缘空间当作现实世界
You're gonna be lost down there so long that you're gonna become an old man.
你迷失于此 直至终老
Filled with regret?
心存遗憾?
Waiting to die alone.
孤独离世
I'll come back.
我会回来
And we'll be young men together again.
我们再重回年轻那时
Breathe.
呼吸
These people are gonna kill us if we don't give them the combination.
若不告诉他们密码 我们必死无疑
- They just wanna ransom us. - I heard them.
- 他们只求钱财 - 我听他们说
They're gonna lock us in that van, and then drive it into the river.
他们会把我们锁进货车 然后丢到河里
All right. What is in the safe?
箱内有什么东西
Something for you.
是给你的
Maurice always said it was his most precious gift to you.
令尊说过 那是给你最珍贵的礼物
- A will. - Maurice's will is with Port and Dunn.
- 一份遗嘱 - 他的遗嘱在律师那里
That's an alternate.
另一份遗嘱
This would supersede the other if you want it to.
这份具有优先法律效力
It splits up the component businesses of Fischer Morrow.
若你接受 会解体非榭公司
It'd be the end of the entire empire as we know it.
摧毁整家公司
Destroying my whole inheritance?
毁掉给我的全部遗产?
- Why would he suggest such a thing? - I just don't know.
- 他为什么要这样 - 我不知道
He loved you, Robert.
他痛惜你 路裴
In his own way.
以他的方式痛惜你
At the end...
他弥留之际
...he called me in to his deathbed.
他叫我到床边
He could barely speak.
他都说不出话
But he took the trouble to tell me one last thing.
但他尽力说了句话
He pulled me close.
他拉近我
And I could only make out...
我勉强听到
...one word.
两个字
"Disappointed."
失望
When were you in limbo?
你几时去过意识边缘
You might have the rest of the team convinced to carry on with this job.
你也许可以说服其他人继续任务
- But they don't know the truth. - Truth? What truth?
- 因为他们不知道内情 - 什么内情
The truth that, at any minute, you might bring a freight train through the wall.
内情就是你随时可让火车穿墙而过
The truth that Mal is bursting through your subconscious.
内情就是美颖又会跑出来
And the truth that, as we go deeper into Fischer...
内情就是越是深入路裴的潜意识
...we're also going deeper into you.
同时亦会深入你潜意识
And I'm not sure we're gonna like what we find.
恐怕后果不堪设想
We were working together.
我们当时在一起工作
We were exploring the concept of a dream within a dream.
探索梦中梦的奥妙
I kept pushing things.
我欲之过急
I wanted to go deeper and deeper. I wanted to go further.
我不断深潜梦空间
I just didn't understand the concept that hours could turn into years down there...
当时我亦未明白
...that we could get trapped so deep...
梦里人生几般变
...that when we wound up on the shore of our own subconscious...
直到最后我们潜入潜意识边缘
... we lost sight of what was real.
我们迷失于此
We created. We built the world for ourselves.
在那里我们费尽所思打造世界
We did that for years.
所费数十载
We built our own world.
建造了属于我们的世界
How long were you stuck there?
你们被困了多久
Something like 50 years.
差不多五十年
How could you stand it?
你怎么受得了
It wasn't so bad at first, feeling like gods.
原先感觉高高在上
The problem was knowing that none of it was real.
问题在于我知道一切都非真实
Eventually, it just became impossible for me to live like that.
后来我终无法再继续如斯生活
And what about for her?
她呢
She had locked something away, something deep inside her.
她将其内心深处的想法深锁起来
A truth that she had once known, but chose to forget.
她本已知道事实 却选择遗忘
Limbo became her reality.
她把那里当成现实世界
What happened when you woke up?
你们醒后发生何事
Well, to wake up from that after years, after decades...
由漫长数十载的梦空间苏醒
... to become old souls thrown back into youth like that?
迟暮之年逆转为而立之年
I knew something was wrong with her. She just wouldn't admit it.
我知道她不对劲 可她就是不承认
Eventually, she told me the truth.
终于她道出实话
She was possessed by an idea.
她仍有所思疑
This one very simple idea that changed everything.
极符其微的意念却足以改变一切
That our world wasn't real.
她思疑这个世界亦非真实
That she needed to wake up to come back to reality...
她很想重回现实世界
...that in order to get back home...
然而为了回到现实
...we had to kill ourselves.
我们就必须自杀
- What about your children? - She thought they were projections...
- 那你们的孩子呢 - 她认为都是潜意识投射影子
... that our real children were waiting for us up there somewhere.
认为真正的孩子在现实中等待我们
I'm their mother!  Calm down.
- 我是他们母亲 - 冷静
I can tell the difference.
我顿觉不妥
If this is my dream, why can't I control this?
若只是场梦 你可以控制它
You don't know you're dreaming!
因为你不知周也
She was certain there was nothing I could do...
她态度强硬 我无法劝服
...no matter how much I begged, no matter how much I pleaded.
不管我苦苦哀求
She wanted to do it, but she could not do it alone.
她想轻生 又不愿独自黄泉路
She loved me too much, so she came up with a plan on our anniversary.
她很爱我 因此在我们结婚周年有所行动
- Sweetheart, what are you doing? - Join me.
- 老婆 你在干什么 - 加入我
Just... Just step back inside. All right? Just step back inside now, come on.
先回屋内
No. I'm going to jump, and you're coming with me.
不 我要跳下去 你跟我一起跳
No, I'm not.
不 我不会跳
Now, you listen to me.
听我讲
If you jump, you're not gonna wake up, remember? You're gonna die.
若跳下去 你永远不会醒过来
Now, just step back inside.
先回屋内
Come on. Step back inside so we can talk about this.
回屋内漫谈
We've talked enough.
谈过多次了
- Mal. - Come out onto the ledge...
- 美颖 - 爬到窗台上来
...or I'll jump right now. - Okay.
否则我马上跳
We're gonna talk about this.
那我们谈谈
All right?
可以吗
- I'm asking you to take a leap of faith. - No, honey.
- 我要你孤注一掷 - 不行
No, I can't. You know I can't do that.
我不能那样做
Take a second, think about our children.
稍微为我们的孩子着想
Think about James.
为占仔着想
Think about Phillipa, now.
为菲丽着想
If I go without you, they'll take them away anyway.
就算你不跳 孩子还会被带走
- What does that mean? - I filed a letter with our attorney...
- 你什么意思 - 我留了封信给我们的律师
...explaining how I'm fearful for my safety.
坦说我担心自身安危
How you've threatened to kill me.
你扬言杀我
- Why did you do this? - I love you, Dom.
- 为什么要这样做 - 我好爱你 杜文
Why did...? Why would you do this to me?
为何如斯对我
I've freed you from the guilt of choosing to leave them.
你不必为离开孩子而自责
We're going home to our real children.
我们是回家看望真正的孩子
Oh, no, no, no, Mal, you listen to me, all right? Mal, look at me, please?
美颖 求你听我讲
You're waiting for a train.
你等待一列火车
- Mal, goddamn it, don't do this! - A train that will take you far away.
- 美颖 不要 - 火车将带你远去他方
James and Phillipa are waiting for you!
占仔和菲丽等待我们
You know where you hope this train will take you, but you can't know for sure.
你深知前去何方 同时亦忧虑能否到达
- Mal, look at me! - But it doesn't matter.
- 美颖 看着我 - 不过无关紧要
- Mal, goddamn it! Mal, listen to me! - Because you'll be together.
- 美颖 听我讲 - 彼此相聚已胜一切
Sweetheart! Look at me! Mal, no!
美颖 不要
She had herself declared sane by three different psychiatrists.
她有三位心理医生出具的精神证明
It made it impossible for me to try to explain the nature of her madness.
我没法解释她发疯原因
So I ran.
所以我只好逃走
Right now, or never, Cobb.
此时不走更待何时
James! Phillipa! Come on in! Come on!
占仔 菲丽 过来
All right, let's go.
好 走
I left my children behind and I've been trying to buy my way back ever since.
我抛下了孩子 我一直很想回家
Your guilt defines her. It's what powers her.
是你的自责感塑造了她
But you are not responsible for the idea that destroyed her.
不要再耿耿于怀
And if we are gonna succeed in this...
若果要行动成功
...you have to forgive yourself, and you're gonna have to confront her.
你要原谅自己 坦然面对她
But you don't have to do that alone.
你不会独自面对
- No, you're not... - I'm doing it for the others.
- 不 你不必… - 我是紧张大局
Because they have no idea the risk they've taken coming down here with you.
因他们对跟你潜入梦空间的风险一无所知
We have to move.
我们得走
Time's up.
时间到了
All right. I don't know any combination.
我真不知道密码
- Not consciously, anyway.  How about instinctively, huh?
- 完全没有印象 - 那用直觉猜
I got somebody in your father's office right now ready to tap in the combination.
我已派人在令尊办公室待命
Give me the first six numbers that come to your head right now.
你快想出六个数字
- I have no idea. - Right now!
- 我真不知道 - 快
I said, right now! Right now!
快
Five, two, eight, four, nine, one.
五、二、八、四、九、一
You'll have to do better than that.
早该如此
All right. Bag them. You're going for a ride.
套起来 我们要上车
We're worth more to you alive. You hear me?
你们想杀人灭口?
What'd you get?
有什么收获
Relationship with his father is worse than we imagined.
他们父子关系比传闻还糟糕
This helps us how?
对我们有用吗
The stronger the issues, the more powerful the catharsis.
越是这样 他就越需要精神发泄
- How are we gonna reconcile them? - I'm working on that.
- 我们怎么令他们和好 - 我在斟酌
Work faster. The projections are closing in quick.
影子们逼近
We gotta break out of here before we're totally boxed in.
我们须在被围堵前突破出去
Damn it.
激死
You mustn't be afraid to dream a little bigger, darling.
只是场梦 不用较真
We need to shift his animosity from his father to his godfather.
现我们要将他对父亲的怨恨转移到教父
- Destroy his one positive relationship? - No, repair his relationship with his father...
- 破坏他们叔侄友好关系? - 不 我们要揭露他叔叔的真面目
...whilst exposing his godfather's true nature.
藉以修复他和父亲的关系
We should charge Fischer a lot more than Saito for this job.
我们做这么多有益他的事 该收费
His security is gonna get worse as we go deeper.
潜入越深 他的意识守护者就越多
- I think we run with Mr. Charles. - No.
我们得用查理先生那招
Who's Mr. Charles? - Bad idea.
- 谁是查理先生 - 馊主意
The second we get into that hotel his security's gonna be all over us.
我们一抵达酒店 守护者就会堤防我们
We run with Mr. Charles like on the Stein job.
然后我们就采取查理计划
- You've done it before?  Yeah, and it didn't work.
- 以前做过? - 但没成功
The subject realized he was dreaming and his subconscious tore us to pieces.
目标人物意识到他在做梦 他潜意识在排斥我们
Excellent. But you learned a lot, right?
好极 不过你们吃一堑长一智
- I need some kind of distraction.  No problem.
- 我需要有人引开注意 - 没问题
How about a lovely lady that I've used before?
像以前那样 伪装成个美女如何
Listen to me. You drive carefully, all right?
小心开车 知道吗
Everything down there is gonna be unstable as hell.
下一层会非常不稳定
Don't jump too soon. We only got one shot at that kick. We gotta make it.
别太早冲下去 只能用一次堕醒
I'll play the music to let you know it's coming. The rest is on you.
时间一时我用音乐提示你们 剩下的就靠你们
- You ready? - Ready!
- 准备好吗? - 就绪
Sweet dreams.
做个美梦
Am I boring you?
你觉得我很无聊吗
I was telling you my story. I guess it wasn't to your liking.
你好像不喜欢听我的故事
Um, I have a lot on my mind.
我现在心乱如麻
There goes Mr. Charles.
查理先生出场
Mr. Fischer, right?
你是非榭先生?
Pleasure to see you again. Rod Green from marketing. L...
乐意再见面 我是营销部的洛・葛明
- And you must be? - Leaving.
- 你是? - 失陪
In case you get bored.
得闲找我
Must've blown you off.
你被她迷倒
That is, unless her phone number really is only six digits.
电话号码怎会只有6位数
Funny way to make friends, someone stealing your wallet like that.
假意结交 继而偷钱包
Goddamn it. The wallet alone is worth at least 500...
单钱包至少价值…
About $500, right?
五百美元?
Don't worry about it. My people are already on it as we speak.
别担心 我的人会帮你把钱包找回来
Who or what is Mr. Charles?
查理先生到底是什么
It's a gambit designed to turn Fischer against his own subconscious.
就是挑拨路裴与意识守护者的关系
And why don't you approve?
你为什么不赞成
It involves telling the mark that he's dreaming...
这会告诉目标人物他置身梦中
...which involves attracting a lot of attention to us.
也会引起注意我们
- Didn't Cobb say never to do that? - Hmm.
杜文不是说不能这么做吗
So now you've noticed how much time...
现在你清楚杜文为人
...Cobb spends doing things he says never to do.
说一套做一套
Mr. Saito, can I have a moment?
齐藤先生 能和你谈谈吗?
- I'm sorry, but...  Hold on! Wait!
- 抱歉… - 等等
You look a bit perkier.
精神甚佳
Very amusing, Mr. Eames.
难以置信 奕祠
Turbulence on the plane?
飞机遇到气流?
No, it's much closer.
守护者快追上
That's Yusuf's driving.
佑沭还在开车
Um, I'm sorry. Who did you say you were?
抱歉 你刚说你是?
Rod Green from marketing.
营销部的洛・葛明
But that's not true at all, is it?
其是没这个人 对不
My name is Mr. Charles. You remember me, don't you?
我是查理先生 还记得吗
I'm the head of your security down here.
我是你这里的保安主管
Get out on a different floor, keep moving.
去不同的楼层 别停下来
Dump the wallet. Security will be looking for that.
然后丢掉皮包 守护者会找的
- Okay. - We need to buy Cobb a little more time.
我们要帮杜文争取多些时间
Security, huh?
保安?
- You work for the hotel? - No, no.
- 你就职这家酒店? - 不是
I specialize in a very specific type of security.
我负责一种很特别的保安工作
Subconscious security.
潜意识保安
You're talking about dreams?
你想说这里是梦空间?
Are you talking about, um, extraction?
有盗梦者入侵?
I am here to protect you.
我会保护你
Mr. Fischer, I'm here to protect you in the event...
非榭先生 我会保护你
...that someone tries to access your mind through your dreams.
防止有人通过梦空间入侵你意识
You're not safe here.
你身处险境
They're coming for you.
他们要来抓你
Strange weather, isn't it?
天气异常 对不
You feel that?
感觉到吗
What's happening?
发生什么事
Cobb's drawing Fischer's attention to the strangeness of the dream...
杜文让路裴觉得这梦空间很怪异
...which is making his subconscious look for the dreamer.
所以他的潜意识在找造梦师
For me. Quick, give me a kiss.
就是我 快吻我
- They're still looking at us. - Yeah, it was worth a shot.
- 影子们还关注我们 - 试试无妨
We should probably get out of here.
我们最好离开这里
You feel that? You've actually been trained for this, Mr. Fischer.
感觉到吗 你曾受过训练
Pay attention to the strangeness of the weather, the shift in gravity.
注意天气异常 重力变化
None of this is real. You're in a dream.
一切皆是梦
Now, the easiest way for you to test yourself...
最简单的梦空间测试就是
...is to try and remember how you arrived at this hotel. Can you do that?
尝试回忆你是如何来到这家酒店
No, breathe, breathe. Remember your training.
呼吸 回想训练
Accept the fact that you're in a dream, and I'm here to protect you. Go on.
相信你置身梦空间 而我是来保护你
- You're not real? - No.
你不是真实?
No. I'm a projection of your subconscious.
我只是你潜意识的投射影子
I was sent here to protect you in the event...
我是来保护安全
...that extractors tried to pull you into a dream.
防止盗梦者带你进入梦空间
And I believe that's what's going on right now, Mr. Fischer.
然而事情已发生
Can you get me out of here?
帮我离开这里
Right away. Follow me.
现在 跟着我
Hold on a second.
稍等
Jesus Christ! What are you doing?
你在干什么
These men were sent here to abduct you, all right?
这些人是来绑架你
If you want my help, you have to remain calm.
要我帮你 你必须保持冷静
I need you to work with me, Mr. Fischer.
我需要你配合
If this is a dream, I should just kill myself to wake up, right?
若这是梦空间 我自杀就会清醒 对吧
I wouldn't do that if I were you, Mr. Fischer.
若我是你就不会这样做
I believe they have you sedated, and if you pull that trigger...
他们肯定给你注射镇静剂
...you may not wake up.
自杀的话是醒不过来
You may go into a further dream state. Now, you know what I'm talking about.
会进入更深的梦空间 你应该明白
You remember the training.
回想训练的内容
Remember what I said to you.
回想我的教导
Give me the gun.
把枪给我
- This room should be directly below 528? - Yeah.
- 这房间刚好在五二八下面吗? - 没错
Think, Mr. Fischer, think.
努力回想
What do you remember from before this dream?
回想发梦前发生的事情
There was, um, a lot of gunfire.
枪林弹雨
There was rain.
倾盆大雨
Uncle Peter.
彼得叔叔
- Oh, my God, we've been kidnapped. - Where were they holding you?
- 我们被绑架 - 他们把你们关在哪
- They had us in the back of a van. - That explains the gravity shifts.
- 关在货车后座 - 难怪会有重力变化
You're in the back of a van. Keep going.
你现正在货车后座 继续
It had something to do with, um...
好像是…
Something to do with a safe.
跟保险箱有关
God, why is it so hard to remember?
我总想不起来
It's like trying to remember a dream after you've woken up.
就像梦醒却难以回忆当中
Listen, it takes years of practice.
需要多年时间训练
You and Browning have been pulled into this dream...
你和彼得被带到此梦空间
...because they're trying to steal something from your mind.
因为他们要从你意识盗取某些信息
I need you to focus and try and remember what that is.
你要集中精神记起究竟是什么信息
What is it, Mr. Fischer? Think!
是什么信息
A combination. They demanded the first numbers to pop into my head.
密码 他们要我说出凭直觉想到的数字
They're trying to extract a number from your subconscious.
他们想从你的潜意识盗取数字密码
It can represent anything. We're in a hotel right now.
数字可以代表很多 就如我们在酒店
We should try hotel rooms. What was the number, Mr. Fischer?
可以试下酒店房间号
Try and remember for me. This is very important.
努力回忆 这非常重要
Five.
五
Five, two... It was something, it was a long number.
五、二 很长的数字密码
That's good. We can start there. Fifth floor.
- 好 我们从这里找起 - 五楼
- So do you use a timer? - No, I have to judge it for myself.
- 用计时器? - 自己判断
While you're all asleep in 528, I wait for Yusuf's kick.
当你们在五二八房入睡 我等候佑沭的堕醒信号
- Well, how will you know? - His music warns me.
- 你怎么知道 - 会有音乐提示
And then when the van hits the barrier of the bridge, that should be unmistakable.
要跟货车撞到桥栏的时间配合无误
So we get a nice synchronized kick.
才能同步堕醒
If it's too soon, we won't get pulled out.
若太早 我们回不去
But if it's too late, I won't be able to drop us.
晚了 我无法堕醒你们
- Well, why not? - Because the van will be in freefall.
- 为什么 - 因为到时候货车于自由落体过程
- Can't drop you without gravity. - Right.
- 没有重力配合实现堕醒 - 有道理
They're with me. Go on.
自己人
Mr. Charles.
查理先生
- Do you know what that is, Mr. Fischer? - Yeah, I think so.
- 知道里面是什么吧 非榭先生 - 我知道
They were trying to put you under.
他们想要把你带入梦空间
- I'm already under. - Under again.
- 我已在梦空间 - 再进去
What do you mean, a dream within a dream?
你所指梦中梦?
Hey. I see you've changed.
你又扮鬼扮马
I'm sorry?
不懂你说什么
Oh, I'm sorry. I mistook you for a friend.
抱歉 认错人了
Good-Iooking fellow, I'm sure.
他肯定样貌标青
No, no, no. That's Fischer's projection of Browning.
那是路裴潜意识投射出来的彼得
Let's follow him and see how he behaves.
跟着看他做什么
- Why? - Because how he acts will tell us...
- 为什么 - 因为他的动作会告诉我们
...if Fischer is starting to suspect his motives the way we want him to.
路裴是否已对彼得起疑了
- Uncle Peter. - You said you were kidnapped together?
- 彼得叔叔 - 你说你们一起被绑架
Well, not exactly. They already had him. They were torturing him.
事实是他们先绑架他 并折磨他
And you saw them torture him?
你亲眼目睹他们折磨他?
The kidnappers are working for you?
绑匪是你安排?
Robert.
路裴
You're trying to get that safe open? To get the alternate will?
你想打开保险箱 拿遗嘱?
Fischer Morrow has been my entire life. I can't let you destroy it.
公司是我毕生心血 我不容许你摧毁
I'm not gonna throw away my inheritance.
我岂会摧毁公司
I couldn't let you rise to your father's last taunt.
我岂能让你再遭受令尊泼冷水
- What taunt? - The will, Robert. That will?
- 泼冷水? - 那份遗嘱
That's his last insult.
就是对你泼冷水
A challenge for you to build something for yourself...
他质疑你会有所建树
...by telling you you're not worthy of his accomplishments.
言下之意 你没资格继承公司
- What, but that he was, um, disappointed? - I'm sorry.
- 他对我很失望? - 很抱歉
But he's wrong.
不过他错了
You can build a better company than he ever did.
果然青出于蓝而胜于蓝
Mr. Fischer? He's lying.
非榭先生 他说谎
- How do you know? - Trust me, it's what I do.
- 你怎么知道 - 相信我 我是行内人
He's hiding something, and we need to find out what that is.
我们要查出他在隐瞒什么
I need you to do the same thing to him that he was going to do to you.
以其人之道 还治其人之身
We'll enter his subconscious and find out what he doesn't want you to know.
我们潜入他潜意识找出当中所隐瞒
All right.
好
He's out. - Wait.
- 他入睡了 - 等等
Whose subconscious are we going into exactly?
我们是要潜入谁的意识
We're going into Fischer's.
当然是路裴
I told him it was Browning's so he'd be a part of our team.
我那样说 只是拉拢成为我们一员
He's gonna help us break into his own subconscious.
他将帮我们潜入他的潜意识
That's right.
没错
Security's gonna run you down hard.
守护者会狂追你
And I will lead them on a merry chase.
我会导演场猫鼠游戏
- Just be back before the kick. - Go to sleep, Mr. Eames.
- 记得准时堕醒我们 - 奕祠 快睡觉
You good?
没事吧
Hey. You ready?
准备好没
Yes, yes. I'm fine. I'm ready.
我没事 可以就绪
Cobb?
杜文
Cobb? What's down there?
杜文 那边是什么
Hopefully, the truth we want Fischer to learn.
希望有我们想让路裴知道的真相
I mean, what's down there for you?
我所指 那里有什么你期待的
Did you see that?
看见没
Eames, this is your dream.
奕祠 这是你的梦空间
I need you to draw the security away from the complex, understand?
你负责把守护者引离基地
- Who guides Fischer in?  Not me.
- 谁带领路裴进去 - 我不行
If I know the route, everything could be compromised.
若我知道路线 行动必定失败
- I designed the place.  No, you're with me.
- 我设计这地方的 - 你要跟着我
I could do it.
我来
All right. Brief him on the route into the complex.
告诉他怎么进入基地
- Fischer, you'll be going with him. - All right. What about you?
- 路裴 你跟着他 - 好 那你呢
You keep this live. I'll be listening in the whole time.
戴好 全程保持联络
The windows on that upper floor are big enough for me to cover you from that tower.
二楼的窗容许我在塔上掩护你
You're not coming in?
你不进去?
In order to find out the truth about your father...
为了找寻令尊的真相
...you're gonna need to break into Browning's mind on your own.
你要独自潜入彼得的意识
Come on, Fischer!
快
- Sound the alarm! Sound the alarm! - Go, go, go!
通知警报
Move!
行动
Sod it.
糟糕
I hope you're ready.
希望你们准备好
No, it's too soon.
太早了
Cobb, do you hear that?
杜文 听到吗
I first noticed it about 20 minutes ago, I thought it was the wind up here.
大约廿分钟前开始听到 我还以为是风声
Yeah, I hear it. It's music.
我听到 是音乐
So, what do we do?
怎么办
We move fast.
动作快点
Yusuf's 10 seconds from the jump.
十秒后佑沭就要开车撞桥栏
Which gives Arthur three minutes.
雅迪有三分钟时间
- Hey! - That's him!
是他
- Which gives us what? - Sixty minutes.
- 我们还剩多久 - 六十分钟
- Can they make that route in an hour? - They have to climb to the terrace.
- 他们能一小时内进去吗? - 他们还得爬中央平台
Then they need a new route, a more direct route.
有没有捷径
It's designed as a labyrinth.
这里本来就设计成迷宫
There must be access routes that cut through the maze.
一定会有捷径通过迷宫
Eames?
奕祠?
Did Eames add any features?
奕祠有没有在迷宫加料
I don't think I should tell you.
我不可以告诉你
We don't have time for this. Did he add anything?
没时间 快告诉我
He added an air-duct system that can cut through the maze.
他加了风道系统以便通过迷宫
Good. Explain it to them.
好极 叫他们换道
Saito? - Go ahead.
- 齐藤 - 收到
Paradox.
似非而是
What was that? - The kick.
- 怎么会这样 - 开始堕醒
Cobb! Cobb, did we miss it?
杜文 我们错过堕醒?
Yeah, we missed it.
我们错过堕醒了
Couldn't someone have dreamt up a goddamn beach? Huh?
为什么不设计个海滩
EAMES : Well, what the hell do we do now?
那我们现在怎么办
We finish the job before the next kick.
下次堕醒前完成任务
- What next kick? - When the van hits the water.
- 下次? - 火车冲击水面时
How do I drop you without gravity?
没有重力怎么实现堕醒
Arthur has a couple minutes, and we have about 20.
雅迪还剩几分钟 我们约有廿分钟
You okay?
没事吧
Run! Turn around! Move to base! Move to base!
返回基地
There's something wrong.
有不妥
They're heading your way, like they know something.
他们如有所觉察 朝着你们方向前去
Just buy us more time, all right?
想办法争取多点时间
All right.
好
Okay. That's the antechamber outside the strong room.
这是保险库的前厅
- Does the strong room have windows? - It wouldn't be very strong if it did.
- 保险库有窗吗 - 有的话就不叫保险库
Let's hope Fischer likes what he finds in there.
希望路裴可如愿以偿
- Are those projections his subconscious? - Yes.
- 这些都是他潜意识的投射影子? - 是
- Are you destroying parts of his mind? - No. They're just projections.
- 你在摧毁他部分潜意识 - 他们只是影子
- We're here. - You're clear, but hurry.
- 我们到了 - 目前安全 但要快点
There's an entire army headed your way.
整支部队朝你们那前去
I'm in.
我进来了
There he is.
他在那
- There's someone in there. - Fischer, it's a trap. Get out.
- 里面还有人 - 是陷阱 快走
Come on. Come on, a little lower.
拜托 再低点
Cobb.
杜文
No, she is not real.
她不是真实的
How do you know that?
你怎么知道
She is just a projection. Fischer. Fischer is real.
她只是影子 路裴才是真实的
Eames! Eames, get to the antechamber now!
奕祠 快赶到前厅
What happened? - Mal killed Fischer.
- 什么事 - 美颖杀死路裴
I couldn't shoot her.
我没法对她开枪
There's no use in reviving him. His mind's already trapped down there.
无法救他 他的意识已被困在下一层
It's all over.
玩完
So that's it, then? We failed?
言下之意 我们失败了?
We're done. I'm sorry.
好抱歉 我们失败了
It's not me that doesn't get back to my family, is it?
反正不是我不能回家
Shame. I wanted to know what was gonna happen in there. I swear we had this.
好可惜 还想知道里面有什么
Let's set the charges.
装炸药
No, there's still another way.
还有其他方法
- We have to follow Fischer down there. - Not enough time.
- 我们只有跟路裴潜入下一层 - 时间不够
No, but there will be enough time down there.
但在下一层有足够时间
And we will find him.
我们会找到他
Okay, as soon as Arthur's music kicks in, just use the defibrillator to revive him.
一旦音乐响 就用电击器电醒他
We can give him his own kick down below.
同时我们在下一层堕醒他
Look, you get him in there.
然后你就可以让他进去里面
As soon as the music ends, you blow up the hospital...
音乐一结束 你就炸掉基地
...and we all ride the kick back up the layers.
我们便能回到现实世界
It's worth a shot, if Saito can hold the guards off while I set the charges.
值得一试 我怕装炸药时 斋藤挡不住士兵
Saito will never make it, will he?
齐藤能坚持吗
- Cobb, come on. We've gotta try this. - Go for it.
- 我们一定要试试 - 好吧
If you are not back before the kick, I am gone with or without you.
时间一到 我可不等你们
She's right. She's right. Come on. Let's go.
她说得对 我们走
Can I trust you to do what needs to happen here?
我能相信你可应付接下来的事吗?
Mal's gonna be down there.
美颖一定在那里
I know where to find her. She'll have Fischer.
我会找到她 她肯定和路裴一起
- How do you know? - Because she wants me to come after him.
- 你怎么知道 - 因为她知道我会去找路裴
She wants me back down there with her.
她要我跟她一起留在那里
All right?
没事吧?
- This is your world? - It was.
- 这是你们的世界 - 曾经是
And this is where she'll be.
她就在这里
Saito. Saito.
齐藤
I need you to take care of Fischer while I go set some charges, okay?
我装炸药 你负责看好路裴
No room for tourists on these jobs.
看来我真的不适合参与
Don't be silly.
别傻了
You built all this? This is incredible.
这些都是你们创建?难以置信
We built for years.
花费数十载创建
Then we started in on the memories.
那时我们凭记忆创建
This way.
这边
This was our neighborhood.
这是我们的小区
Places from our past.
根据昔日记忆创建
That was our first apartment.
那是我们第一套公寓
Then we moved to that building right there.
后来搬到旁边那栋大厦
After Mal became pregnant, that became our home.
美颖有孕后 就住那
You reconstructed all of this from memory?
你们根据记忆记忆创建这一切
Like I told you, we had lots of time.
在这里我们有的是时间
What is that?
那是什么
That's the house Mal grew up in.
美颖成长的地方
- Well, will she be in there? - No.
她会在那吗?
We both wanted to live in a house, but we loved this type of building.
我们都想住别墅 但我们又喜欢这种风格的大厦
In the real world, we'd have to choose, but not here.
现实世界只能二选一 但在这里任由我们话事
How are we gonna bring Fischer back?
我们怎么带路裴回去
We're gonna have to come up with some kind of a kick.
我们要设法堕醒他
What?
怎么堕醒
I'm gonna improvise.
到时临场发挥
Listen, there's something you should know about me. About inception.
关于植入意念 我有件事你要知道
An idea is like a virus. Resilient.
意念如病毒顽强
Highly contagious.
感染力强
And the smallest seed of an idea can grow.
再细微的意念一旦植入 亦能萌芽成长
It can grow to define...
它能成就你
...or destroy you.
亦能摧毁你
The smallest idea, such
再细微的意念
"Your world is not real."
如「我们的世界并非真实」
Simple little thought that changes everything.
极符其微的意念却足以改变一切
So certain of your world. Of what's real.
你肯定所处的世界是真实
Do you think he is?
他也肯定吗?
Or do you think he's as lost as I was?
抑或他也和我一样迷茫?
I know what's real, Mal.
我能辨析真与幻
No creeping doubts?
毫无私疑?
Not feeling persecuted, Dom?
毫无困惑?
Chased around the globe...
受诸通缉
...by anonymous corporations and police forces...
亡命天涯
...the way the projections persecute the dreamer?
梦与实皆是这般
Admit it.
所言甚是?
You don't believe in one reality anymore.
你根本不相信所谓的现实
So choose.
做选择
Choose to be here.
选择留下与我
Choose me.
长相思守
You know what I have to do.
你知道我身负重则
I have to get back to our children because you left them.
我必须回到孩子身边
Because you left us.
皆因你抛弃我们
- You're wrong.  I'm not wrong.
- 讲大话 - 我没讲大话
You're confused.
你多疑
Our children are here.
我们的孩子在这里
And you'd like to see their faces again, wouldn't you?
想不想再看看他们
Yes, but I'm gonna see them up above, Mal.
想 但我要回到现实世界去看他们
Up above?
现实世界?
Listen to yourself. These are our children.
别痴人说梦 他们就在这
Watch.
看
James? Phillipa?
占仔?菲丽?
Don't do this, Mal. Please. Those aren't my children.
别这样 他们不是我的孩子
You keep telling yourself that, but you don't believe it.
你根本口说心非
- No, I know it. - What if you're wrong?
- 我很清楚 - 若果你错了?
What if I'm what's real?
若果我才是真实的
You keep telling yourself what you know.
你不断灌输自己何为所信
But what do you believe?
究竟何为所信
What do you feel?
何为所觉
Guilt.
自责
I feel guilt, Mal.
我好自责
And no matter what I do, no matter how hopeless I am...
无论我做什么 无论我多绝望
...no matter how confused, that guilt is always there...
无论我多迷惘 自责感总
...reminding me of the truth.
不断提醒我事实的真相
What truth?
真相?
That the idea that caused you to question your reality came from me.
是我让你怀疑一切
You planted the idea in my mind?
你对我植入意念?
What is she talking about?
她在说什么
The reason I knew inception was possible was because I did it to her first.
皆因我对她实验过 我才坚持植入意念是可行
- I did it to my own wife. - Why?
- 我对内子植入意念 - 为什么
We were lost in here.
我们迷失于此
I knew we needed to escape, but she wouldn't accept it.
我知我们须逃离梦空间 可她不允
She had locked something away, something deep inside.
她将其内心深处的想法深锁起来
A truth that she had once known, but chose to forget.
她本已知道事实 却选择遗忘
And she couldn't break free.
她不愿释放内心深处的想法
So I decided to search for it.
所以我决定寻找她深锁的东西
I went deep into the recess of her mind and found that secret place.
我潜入她意识 找寻深锁之地
And I broke in...
我找寻到
... and I planted an idea.
并植入意念
A simple little idea that would change everything.
极符其微的意念却足以改变一切
That her world wasn't real.
就是她所处的世界不是真实
That death was the only escape.
死亡是唯一逃离方法
You're waiting for a train.
你等待一列火车
A train that'll take you far away.
火车将带你远去他方
You know where you hope this train will take you...
你深知前去何方
...but you can't know for sure.
同时亦忧虑能否到达
Yet it doesn't matter.
不过无关紧要
- Now, tell me why! - Because you'll be together!
- 告诉我为什么 - 彼此相聚已胜一切
But I never knew that that idea would grow in her mind like a cancer...
我不知此意念如癌症迅速扩散
... that even after she woke...
甚至你醒来后
That even after you came back to reality...
甚至你回到现实世界后
...that you'd continue to believe your world wasn't real.
你仍相信所处的世界非真实
That death was the only escape.
死亡是唯一逃离方法
Mal, no! Jesus!
美颖 不要
- You infected my mind. - I was trying to save you.
- 你潜入我意识 - 我本是想救你
You betrayed me.
你背弃我
But you can make amends. You can still keep your promise.
你还来得及补救 来得及兑现誓言
We can still be together, right here...
留在我们创建的世界
...in the world we built together.
一起双宿双栖
Cobb, we need to get Fischer.
我们要去找路裴
You can't have him.
你们找不到他
- Lf I stay here, will you let him go? - What are you talking about?
- 若我留下 你可以让他离开吗? - 你在说什么
Fischer is on the porch.
路裴在走廊
- Go check he's alive, Ariadne. - Cobb, you can't do this.
- 检查他是否在生 - 你不能这么做
Go check he's alive right now. Do it.
快检查他是否在生
He's here! And it's time, but you have to come now!
他在这 时间到了 你得快来
You take Fischer with you, all right? - You can't stay here to be with her.
- 你带路裴回去 - 你不能跟她留在这
I'm not. Saito's dead by now.
齐藤死了
That means he's down here somewhere. That means I have to find him.
那他也在这地方 我得去找他
I can't stay with her anymore, because she doesn't exist.
我不会跟个虚幻的人留守此处
I'm the only thing you do believe in anymore.
我是你眼前唯一真实的人
I wish.
敢情是
I wish more than anything, but...
我好希望你是真实
...I can't imagine you with all your complexity...
我无法想象到完整的你
...all your perfection, all your imperfection.
无法想象到理想的你与不理想的你
- You all right? - Yeah.
没事吧
Look at you.
看看你
You're just a shade. You're just a shade of my real wife.
你只是个影子 只是我真实内子的影子
And you were the best that I could do, but...
是我想象出的最好投影影子
...I'm sorry, you're just not good enough.
很抱歉 你还不够好
Does this feel real?
这样感觉真实吗
- What are you doing? - Improvising.
- 你在做什么 - 临场发挥
In there, now. Go, go, go.
快进去
I was dis...
我很…
I was dis... Disa...
很失望
- I know, Dad. - Dis...
我知道
I know you were disappointed...
我知道你很失望
...I couldn't be you.
我远不及你
I was disappointed...
我之所以失望…
...that you tried.
皆因你试图效我所为
What?
什么?
That's the kick, Ariadne! You have to go now!
开始堕醒 爱莲 快走
Don't lose yourself! Find Saito and bring him back!
别迷失自我 要带斋藤回来
I will!
我会的
You remember when you asked me to marry you?
仍记得你求婚时的话语吗
Yes.
仍记得
You said you dreamt that we'd grow old together.
你说你梦见们白头偕老
But we did.
我们皆可实现
We did. You don't remember?
我们曾经白头偕老 还记得吗
I miss you more than I can bear...
我想你想到无法忍受
...but we had our time together.
至少我们曾双宿双栖
And I have to let you go.
我是时候放开你
I have to let you go.
我必须放开你
I'm sorry, Robert.
对不起
You know, the will means that Dad wanted me to be my own man...
知道吗 份遗嘱是要我另创天地
...not just to live for him.
而非承袭父荫
That's what I'm gonna do, Uncle Peter.
我正有此意
What happened?
什么事
- Cobb stayed. - With Mal?
- 杜文留在那里 - 和美颖一起?
No, to find Saito.
不 是去找齐藤
He'll be lost.
他将会迷失自我
No, he'll be all right.
他会没事
Have you come to kill me?
你是前来杀我
I'm waiting for someone.
我在等待一个人
Someone from a half-remembered dream.
一个隐约在梦中见过的人
Cobb?
高比?
Impossible.
不可能
We were young men together.
我们曾时值年轻
I'm an old man.
我现已步入迟暮之年
Filled with regret.
终身抱怨
Waiting to die alone.
孤独终老
I've come back for you.
我是回来找你
To remind you of something.
帮你回忆一些事
Something you once knew.
一些你曾记得的事
That this world is not real.
这个世界并非真实
To convince me to honor our arrangement?
要我遵守协议
To take a leap of faith, yes.
没错 冒险一试
Come back...
回去吧
...so we can be young men together again.
重返年轻时
Come back with me.
跟我回去
Come back.
回去
FLIGHT  Hot towel, sir?
先生 需要热毛巾吗
We'll be landing in Los Angeles in about 20 minutes.
飞机约廿分钟后会降落洛杉矶机场
Do you need immigration forms?
需要入境登记表吗?
Thank you.
有劳
Hot towel, sir?
先生 需要热毛巾吗
- No. - Do you need immigration forms?
需要入境登记表吗?
Welcome home, Mr. Cobb.
欢迎回家 高比先生
Thank you, sir.
多谢
Welcome.
欢迎
This way.
这边
James? Phillipa?
占仔 菲丽
Look who's here.
看谁在这
- Hey, guys! Hey! How are you?  Daddy! Daddy!
你们好
Daddy!  How are you?
你们过得怎样
Look what I've been building!
看我堆砌了什么
- What are you building?  We're building a house on the cliff!
- 是什么 - 我们在悬崖上建了座房子
On the cliff? Come on, I want you to show me. Can you show me?
悬崖上?快带我去看看